[Dave:] This is Brian Gawalt who works on text analysis,
这是 Brian Gawalt 他从事文本分析
which is a really important problem for search engines if we want to be able to do
这对搜索引擎是一个非常重要的问题 如果我们想能够
a better job of identifying the right documents.
更好地确定合适的文档的话
Tell us how that works.
请谈谈那是如何运作的
[Brian:] There are lots of different approaches, but the model that we tend to take
有很多不同的方法 但我们倾向于采取的模型
transforms them into a really nice hashtable representation.
将它们转换成一个典型的哈希表表示
Text is long and unwieldy and unstructured and prose flows and goes,
文本很长 难处理 没有结构 散文比较随意
but computers like things that are nice and structured
但计算机是非常有结构的
and amenable in familiar things like lists, hashtables, etc.
而且有人们熟悉的东西 如列表、哈希表等
What we've got is a way to turn unstructured text
我们有一种方式把非结构化的文本
into a data structure that computers are really happy with.
转成为计算机善于处理的数据结构
One of those is the hashtable and the ???.
其中之一是哈希表
We can start with a document that says, "Obama announces candidacy,"
我们首先看看这个文档上写着 "Obama announces candidacy"
and we can turn that into a representation of that document, and imperfect representation
我们可以将此转成该文档的表示形式 不完美的表示形式
that just says let's keep track of every word and the number of times that word appeared
让我们跟踪每一个字和
in the document.
字在文档中出现的次数
We would just go through and say "Obama"--go to the hashtable and hash Obama
我们仔细查看 说"Obama"——去哈希表 哈希奧巴馬
and make sure the value associated with it is 1.
并确保与它关联的值是1
Similarly, "announces" hashes to 1, and "candidacyO hashes to 1.
同样地 "announces"哈希值为1 "candidacy"的哈希值为1
If we were dealing with longer documents, these values would grow,
如果我们处理更长的文档 这些值将会增长
and the number of elements in the hashtable would grow as well.
哈希表中元素的数字也将变大
Then we come across document 2, and we can represent that with a whole new hashtable.
然后我们看到了文档2 我们可以用一个全新的哈希表表示文档2
"Barak Obama elected"--Barak maps to 1, Obama maps to 1, and elected maps to 1.
"Barak Obama elected"——Barak 映射到1 Obama 映射到1 elected 映射到1
If it also said "President" down here, we'd add more and more keys
如果它还说"President" 我们将在这下边添加更多的键
and keep track of the value associated with each one.
跟踪每个关联的值
When it comes time to relate documents to each other, like we would do with our search engine,
但使文档相互关联时 比如说我们会用搜索引擎来操作
we can look and say, hey, there's an overlap between these two documents
我们可以看着 然后说 嘿 这两个文件之间有重叠
and the fact that they both used "Obama."
他们都使用了"Obama"
If we've got enough documents and there are enough patterns between them,
如果我们有足够的文档 它们之间有足够的模式
then we can start saying I'm seeing this pattern of "Barak" shows up in a lot of them
那么 就可以开始说 我看到"Barak"这一模式在许多文档中出现了
or "candidacy" or "announcements" seem to come from him a lot.
或者"candidacy"或"announcements"似乎都和他相关
Now you've got a way of expanding this key word that maybe we're searching for "Obama"
现在你有一种方式扩大这个关键词 也许我们在搜索"Obama"
and the search engine can think when you say "Obama" you're really talking about
在当你说"Obama"的时候 搜素引擎会想
this wide pantheon of topics that all of the do with the 44th presidency.
你在谈论所有与第44届总统相关的宽泛的话题
[Dave:] How did you get started working on this?
你是如何开始这工作的？
[Brian:] Well, I was an electrical engineer, and I went from circuits to signals
嗯 我以前是一个电气工程师 和我打交道的是电路、信号
to statistical signal processing, and it turns out I was working on how to tell
统计信号处理 后来发现原来我做的工作是如何判断
if a cell phone is sending a 1 or a 0, and the math behind that wound up being
一部手机是否正在发送1或0 背后涉及的数学
broadly applicable to general problems, including how to tell if an email is spam or not.
广泛适用于一般的问题 包括如何判断一封电子邮件是否是垃圾邮件
That's kind of the entrance to text processing in general from my background.
从我的背景来看 这就像是一个文本处理的入口
[Dave:] I see. So what's the next step then?
明白了 下一步呢？
Well, a lot of the stuff that we work with all comes down to being able to compare
嗯 我们工作中涉及的很多东西都归结为
two documents and then finding out how that comparison matches
比较两个文档 然后找出比较
to whatever you're target is--detecting spam or not.
和你的目标如何匹配——检测是否是垃圾邮件
All that works really well if the documents are next to each other,
如果文档是相邻的 一切都进行地很顺利
living close to each other within a single system,
在单个系统中彼此贴近
but that gives you a maximum of how many documents get analyzed.
但这会限制你最多很有分析多少文档
So distributing the solutions to these problems
所以分配解决方案给这些问题
is, I think, where a lot of energy is being put forth.
我认为 需要大量的能量